Crystal Yan 408.899.96711 yan.crystal.c@gmail.com

Product management and design leader focused on transforming organizations to become more customer-centric. Experience using behavioral science and artificial intelligence to create meaningful user experiences for B2B and B2C products globally.

EXPERIENCE

Product Manager & Product Design Manager — FiscalNote, Washington, DC MAR 2016 - PRESENT

- · Landed first enterprise client with total contract value (TCV) that grew company revenue by 10% by setting vision and roadmap of product portfolio generating > \$8M annual recurring revenue (ARR), including launching new EU, South America, and Asia product lines for web and mobile.
- Doubled product team in headcount and reduced ramp-up time for new hires by 50% by developing interviewer guides and onboarding program; report directly to COO/VP of Product.
- Designed new features and product lines that grew average contract value (ACV) from 43.54% from 2015 Q4 to 2016 Q3 by leading the full-stack design discovery process (lead design sprints, conduct qualitative and quantitative user experience (UX) research with interviews and metrics analysis; lead ideation and wireframing; create interactive high-fidelity prototypes, and test with users to validate hypotheses), leading delivery sprints with engineering and QA, and planning go-to-market strategy with marketing, sales, and client success teams.

Freelance Designer & Product Strategy Consultant — Independent, Remote AUG 2015 - MAR 2016

- UX Design Lead for MyHealthEd, Inc, a nonprofit transforming sex education with storytelling. Contributed to raising \$50K in funding and launching beta product by leading the UX and interaction design for an app designed for 13-14 year old low-income teens in rural areas.
- Curriculum Design Consultant for the DC Mayor's Office Summer Youth Employment Program.
- Design Lead for Rise, a civil rights NGO advocating for a Sexual Assault Survivors' Bill of Rights.

Associate Product Manager & Associate UX Researcher/Designer —

FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2015 - MAR 2016

- · Launched company's first iOS app in four months with one engineer by producing hi-fidelity prototypes, running usability testing and beta testing, and iterating based on user feedback.
- · Aligned executive team (heads of product, sales, client success, and marketing) by developing user personas that guide product strategy, marketing campaign targeting, and sales strategy.
- · Improve site performance and remove user interface (UI) inconsistencies and lines of legacy code by developing the first style guide, UI asset and UX pattern library.

Business Development Associate — FiscalNote, Washington, DC

AUG 2014 - AUG 2015

- Contributed to company raising \$18 million in funding by consistently exceeding sales quotas and closing \$386,842 in new revenue (34% of company revenue) from new clients (Uber, Lyft, FireEye, Akin Gump, Coinbase) with shortest sales cycles, and increasing inbound leads by 36% by developing content marketing and improving SEO as interim Head of Marketing.
- Grew ACV by 76.82% by leading and developing training for 35+ new hires on optimal ways to structure pricing and contract terms in order to maximize ACV and improve cash flow.

Corporate Development Strategy — Innovation Works, Beijing, China OCT 2012 - DEC 2013

• Diversified firm revenue by conducting due diligence & analysis with recommendation to spin part of China's premier early-stage VC firm's in-house UX team into an external UX studio.

Product Manager - Mobile, Standard Chartered Bank, Shanghai, China AUG 2012 - SEP 2012

- · Increased inbound leads and reduced product support costs by leading product development & user testing for a bilingual (English/Mandarin) iPad app for small business owners.
- Cut development costs by 27% by analyzing vendor supplier data to identify excess expenses.

SKILLS

Management:

Interviewing, Hiring, Training, Leading **Design Sprints** User Research: Data Analysis, Contextual Inquiry, User Testing **Design:** Interaction, UI & Visual (Sketch, Adobe CS), Mobile, Prototyping (InVision)

SPEAKING

StarsConf 2017 Santiago, Chile RubyConf 2017 Medellin, Colombia **Grace Hopper 2017** Orlando, FL **Scenic City Summit** Chattanooga, TN **UXDC 2017** Washington, DC **ULLConf 2016** Killarney, Ireland AIGA DotGovDesign Washington, DC

AWARDS

Beijing, China

McKinsey NGWL '17

Microsoft Research

EDUCATION

Amherst College BA, Economics, 2014 **Tsinghua University** International Affairs Beijing, Fall 2012 **International Honors Program Urban Planning &**

Anthropology Delhi, Dakar, Buenos Aires, Spring 2013